Inventory of the United States. Foreign Broadcast Intelligence Service miscellaneous records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Sound Recordings, 1941-1946
  - State-sponsored broadcasts, 1942-1944
    - Radio Tokyo, Australia, and Voice of China radio broadcasts, 1942 May (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Recording #161, Radio Tokyo and Australian broadcasts
      Part 2: Recording #161, Australian broadcast
      Part 3: Recording #161, Radio Tokyo broadcast
      Part 4: Recording #162, Voice of China
    - Radio Tokyo, Radio Chungking, and Radio Saigon broadcasts, 1942 March 15-16 (Record cabinet)
      Radio Tokyo gives an update on the war and provides advice for America.
    - Radio Tokyo, Voice of China, Australian, and Radio Saigon broadcasts, 1942 February 8 (Record cabinet)
      #69
      TOKYO, 400, 2-8-42
      CK, 600A, 2-8-42
      #70
      MB, 730A, 2-8-42
      SAIG, 740A, 2-8-42
    - Radio Tokyo, Voice of China, and Australia radio broadcasts, numbers 177-178, circa 1942 June 7-8 (Record cabinet)
      Inside-Tokyo-June 7 or 8
      Outside Chungking
      #177
      June 1942
    - Radio Tokyo, Voice of China, and Australian radio broadcasts, 1942 May 29-30 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: #155, Radio Tokyo
      Part 2: #155, Voice of China
      Part 3: #155, Radio Tokyo reads American soldiers' letters home.
      Part 4: #156, Radio Tokyo reads American soldiers' letters home.
      Part 5: #156, Australian radio broadcast from 9:30P, 29 May 1942
      Part 6: #156, Big band jazz
      Part 7: #156, Australian radio broadcast from 4:30A, 30 May 1942
    - Radio broadcasts, 1940 March 20-21 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: The Voice of China speaks about U.S. Gen Stilwell before providing a general news update of the war.
    - Radio broadcasts, 1942 March 27-28 (Record cabinet)
      CK, 800A, 3/27/42
      AUST, 100A, 3/28/42
      TK, 200A, 3/28/42
    - Radio broadcasts from Tokyo, Austraila, and Delhi, 1942 March 15 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Side A:
      TK, 500A, 3/15/42
      Part 2: Side B:
      AUST, 730A, 3/15/42
      Part 3: Side B:
      DELHI, 845A, 3/15/42
      TK, 400P, 3/15/42
    - Radio transmissions, 1943 March 1-8 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: #3 - 6:30-3:33, 7:00-7:10 - 1 Mar 1943
      Side B: #3 - 7:04-7:15 - 8 Mar 1943
    - Radio transmissions, 1943 February 15-17 (Record cabinet)
      Radio transmissions recorded off the airwaves.
      Side A: 7:10-7:14 on 15 Feb 1943, transmission from 17 Feb 1943
      Side B: 6:45-6:59 on 17 Feb 1943
    - Radio transmissions, 1943 March 11 (Record cabinet)
      6:09-6:22, 6:23-6:31, 7:00-7:05
    - Radio transmissions, 1942 March 14 (Record cabinet)
      3/14/42
      TK
      400P
      500A
    - Radio transmissions, 1942 January 24-25, February 1 (Record cabinet)
      These recordings are English-language radio broadcasts. Some sound like American-produced programs, others like Asian-produced programs.
    - Radio transmissions, 1942 January 26, February 1 (Record cabinet)
      These radio transmissions concern the Australian, Chinese, Vietnamese, and Japanese experiences in World War II.
    - Radio transmissions, 1942 March 31-April 1 (Record cabinet)
      #206
      TK, (1115P), 1030P, 3/31/42
      AUST, 1201A MIDNITE, 4/1/42
      #205
      200A
      4-1-42
    - Radio transmissions, 1942 April 8-9 (Record cabinet)
      Side A label reads: 95
      CH, 940P, 4-8-42
      TK, 400P, 4-8-42
      #215
      Side B label reads: TK 700P, 4/8/42
      TK 200A, 4/9/42
      TK 400P, 4/9/42
      #216
    - Radio transmissions, 1942 April 27 (Record cabinet)
      Side A label reads: Inside [???]
      Tokyo
      Outside Chungking #229
      Apr 27, 1942?
      Side B label reads: Inside
      Tokyo + Australia
      Outside - Chungking
      About Apr ?1-3? 1942
      #230
    - Recording concerning Bangkok and Saigon, 1942 November 22 (Record cabinet)
    - Sound recording, 6:02-6:23, 1943 February 17 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: 2/17/43 #1
      after first inch
      6:02-6:23
      Part 2: Unidentified music recording
      Part 3: Unidentified broadcast
      Part 4: Unidentified broadcast
      Part 5: Unidentified broadcast
    - Sound recordings 233 and 234, 1942 April 19-May 3 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: War news from Australia, Voice of China broadcast on war news.
    - Sound recordings 235 and 236, 1942 April (Record cabinet)
      These recordings are various news broadcasts updating the listener on war efforts in the Pacific as well as some domestic issues, such as higher education in China (in number 235 / part 1).
    - Sound recordings 237 and 238, 1942 April (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: #237, POW letters home, war news roundup.
      Part 2: #238, War news roundup, especially as applied to Australia.
    - Sound recordings, 1942 December 26, 1943 January 3 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: 3 Jan 1943
      Part 2: Bangk, 26 Dec 1942, 6:00-6:29
    - Sound recordings, 1943 April 3 (Record cabinet)
      Side A label reads:6:07-6:29
      4/3/43 #1
      A note on the original sleeve label reads:4/3/43 #1+2.
      I think a large part after 6:30 is not news, but there was no gong till 6:45, so I cut it all. The reception till 7:07 was very bad, so I missed some of that part.
    - Thai from Bangkok, 6:00 AM, sound recording, 1942 November 20 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Thai from Bangkok
      11/20/42 - 6.00AM
      BB recorded - 33rpm inside out
      Part 2 is not described.
    - Thai from Bangkok on 24 November, 06:00 AM, and 15 January, 06:59, sound recordings, 1942-1943 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: 11/24/42 Thai from Bangkok
      600 AM
      Part 2: 1/15 #3, 6:59-7:10
    - Thai radio broadcasts, 1943 April 1 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: 6:06 - 6:28
      Part 2: 6:29 - 6:53
    - Tokyo Board of Information, Radio Tokyo, Voice of China recordings, 1942 February 6 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: The first cut is a news report. The second cut is soldiers' notes home from Japan. The third cut is also a news report.
      Side B is a single cut Voice of China news report and editorial transmission to North America regarding the Asian theater of the war.
      Cuts sound like they were recorded from airwaves.
    - Unidentified Asian radio broadcast, 1943 February 15 (Record cabinet)
      2/15/43
      6.00 all news
      ou
      #2
    - Unidentified Asian radio broadcasts, 1943 January 2-5 (Record cabinet)
      Side A label reads: 1/2/43 #1, 6:05-6:29
      Side B label reads: 1/5 #3, outside, 7:06-7:16. Side B has two cuts on it.
    - Unidentified Asian radio broadcasts, 1943 February 20 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: The source disc label reads: 7:01 - 7:06, #3
      Part 2: The source disc label reads: 7:07 - 7:11, #4
    - Voice of China and Australia Calling radio broadcasts, 1942 January 10 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: The Voice of China provides an update on the war.
      Part 2: Australia Calling radio report similarly provides war news, especially as it applies to the United Kingdom's interest in the Pacific War.
    - Voice of China and Australia Calling radio broadcasts, 1942 January 12 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Voice of China
      Part 2: Australia Calling
      Both programs offer an update on the war.
    - Voice of China and Australian radio broadcasts, numbers 227-228, 1942 April 22 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: #227, A Voice of China news roundup, mostly about the Pacific Theater, but includes a discussion about Franco's relationship with Europe and the United States.
      Part 2: #227, Radio Tokyo
      Part 3: #228, Voice of China
      Part 4: #228, Australia
      Part 5: #228, Voice of China
    - Voice of China and Radio Tokyo broadcasts, 1942 February 11 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: The Voice of China provides a news update on the war before reading an article examining the relationship between Japan and Germany.
    - Voice of China and Radio Tokyo broadcasts, 1942 February 14 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: The Voice of China provides a news update on a variety of stories, from snow in Chungking to the war. Radio Tokyo broadcasts letters home from American prisoners-of-war.
      Part 2: Radio Tokyo provides the news on the war. It then reads letters home from American prisoners-of-war.
    - Voice of China and Radio Tokyo broadcasts, 1942 January 15 (Record cabinet)
      Part 2: Radio Tokyo
    - Voice of China and Radio Tokyo broadcasts, 1942 February 17 (Record cabinet)
      The Voice of China, broadcasting from Chungking, and Radio Tokyo each provide an update of the fighting in the Pacific Theater of World War II. A strong focus on the news is the fall of Singapore. Radio Tokyo also broadcasts letters home from American prisoners.
    - Voice of China and Radio Tokyo broadcasts, 1942 March 18 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: The Voice of China 745A broadcast is a reading of articles intended for United Press. The first concerns the production of war supplies by China. The second concerns ending the currencies black market.
      The Voice of China 800A broadcast concerns the foreign relations of the Chinese government.
      Part 2: The Voice of China 800A broadcast is a roundup of news in the war.
      Part 3: A Radio Tokyo broadcast of letters home from American prisoners-of-war.
      Part 4: A Radio Tokyo broadcast about the Japanese advances on China.
      Part 5: A Radio Tokyo broadcast about the Japanese advances throughout the Pacific.
      Part 6: A Radio Tokyo news roundup of various stories.
    - Voice of China and Radio Tokyo broadcasts, 1942 March 9 (Record cabinet)
      Side A (Part 1) has two grooves in it. The label reads:
      CK, 400A, 3/9/42
      Side B (Part 2) has four grooves on it. The center label reads:
      TK, 500A, 3/9/42
      TK, 400P, 3/9/42
    - Voice of China and Radio Tokyo broadcasts, numbers 115-116, 1942 February 1 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Recording 115, 600A
      Part 2: Recording 116, 400A
    - Voice of China and Radio Tokyo radio broadcasts, 1942 January 19 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: #35 Voice of China (XGOY, Chungking)
      Side B: #36 Radio Tokyo
    - Voice of China and Radio Tokyo radio broadcasts, 1942 March 17-22 (Record cabinet)
      CK, 800A, 3/17/42
      TK, 900P, 3/17/42
      TK, 500A, 3/18/42
      TK, 1030P, 3-22-42
    - Voice of China and Saigon radio broadcasts, 1942 January 9 (Record cabinet)
      Part 2: Saigon
    - Voice of China broadcasts, 1942 February 4 (Record cabinet)
      The Voice of China describes two articles in the media. It also provides a general update on the war.
      Additional, unrelated music broadcasts are also on the original disc.
    - Voice of China radio broadcast and coded signal transmission sound recordings, 1942 March 11 (Record cabinet)
      3-11-42
      PLV
      2
    - Voice of China radio broadcasts from 28 January and Radio Tokyo broadcast from 29 January, 1942 (Record cabinet)
      #65
      CHUNGKING, 6:45A UP, 1-28-42
      TOKYO, 930P, 1-29-42
      #66
      British Article
      1-28-42
    - Voice of China radio transmissions, 1942 February 9 (Record cabinet)
      These recordings were made from the airwaves.
      On side A, #139, a reporter for the Voice of China describes events in China, including a meeting of Chinese dignitaries and news about the war effort.
      Side B concerns China, Japan, and other locations in Southeast Asia (Rangoon, Singapore, etc.).
    - Voice of China, Australian radio, and Radio Tokyo broadcasts, numbers 165-166, 1942 June 17 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: #165, Voice of China
      Part 2: #165, Voice of China
      Part 3: #165, Australia
      Part 4: #166, Australia
      Part 5: #166, Australia
      Part 6: #166, Radio Tokyo
    - Voice of China, Australian radio, and Radio Tokyo broadcasts, numbers 179-180, 1942 June (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: #179, Voice of China
      Part 2: #179, Australia
      Part 3: #180, Radio Tokyo
      Part 4: #180, Australia
      Part 5: #180, Radio Tokyo. Messages of American POWs.
    - Voice of China, Australian radio, and Radio Tokyo broadcasts, numbers 201-202, 1942 April (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: #201, Voice of China
      Part 2: #201, Australia
      Part 3: #201, Australia
      Part 4: #201, Radio Tokyo fades into Australia
      Part 5: #201, Radio Tokyo reports on the Japan-Thai alliance.
      Part 6: #202, Voice of China
      Part 7: #202, Radio Tokyo
    - Voice of China, Radio Saigon, Radio Tokyo, and Melbourne radio broadcasts, numbers 117-118, 1942 February 2 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: #117, Voice of China, 600A
      Part 2: #117, Radio Saigon, 745A
      Part 3: #118, Radio Tokyo, 640A
      Part 4: #118, Melbourne, 730A
    - Voice of China, Radio Tokyo, and Australian radio broadcasts, number 211-212, 1942 April 3 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: #211, Chungking, 820A, 4-3-42. The Voice of China analyzes Chinese action in Burma.
      Part 2: Radio Tokyo broadcasts American POWs' messages home.
      Part 3: #212, Tokyo, 710P, 4-3-42. Radio Tokyo news roundup and message home from US soldiers.
      Part 4: Australian news
    - Voice of China, Radio Tokyo, and Australian radio broadcasts, numbers 151-152, 1942 May (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: #151, Voice of China. A news roundup. Included in this is a discussion of food availability and prices.
      Part 2: #151, Non-program signals. They were cut onto the disc as two separate cuts.
      Part 3: #152, Radio Tokyo news roundup.
      Part 4: #152, A short, anti-Semitic propaganda program.
      Part 5: #152, Short clip of classical music.
      Part 6: #152
    - Voice of China, Radio Tokyo, and Radio Saigon broadcasts on 7 January and Radio Tokyo broadcast on 26 March, 1942 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: The Voice of China reports the news of the war, especially as it applied to the Hunan capitol.
      Radio Tokyo reports on the advances of the Japanese forces, such as at Hong Kong and Kuala Lumpur.
      Part 2: A broadcast from Saigon gives a roundup of news from the Pacific Theater of the war.
  - American correspondent reports, 1941-1946
    Sound recordings of American journalists reporting from the Pacific Theater of World War II on the advances of the United States' armed forces, the subsequent occupation, and Operation Crossroads.
    - Administrative radio transmission, 1944 December 4 (Record cabinet)
      Job 92
      Dec 4 44
      Gaum Talk Back
      Thornton
      #188
    - Administrative radio transmissions, 1944 December 3 (Record cabinet)
      This is an administrative transmission about a report from Leslie Nichols.
    - Admiral Nimitz and Jack Mahon radio reports, 1945 April (Record cabinet)
      Disc 341: After issuing a communiqué, Admiral Nimitz speaks about the American invasion of Okinawa.
      Following, Jack Mahon comments on the news, providing context.
    - American Red Cross and Jack Mahon radio reports, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      In part 1, a reporter for the American Red Cross interviews American soldiers that have just been freed from Japanese captivity.
      In part 2, Jack Mahon reports from sea about the last victory over the Japanese.
    - American journalist radio reports concerning World War II, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Jack Mahon reports in the first cut, though most of his words are unintelligible due to interference noises.
      Bob Brumby reports from Tokyo on an attempt by him and others to take over Radio Tokyo. His words are also jammed in parts, though most is intelligible, if of poor sound quality.
      Two other journalists interview Major Pappy Boyington, recipient of the Congressional Medal of Honor. Boyinton recalls being shot down and being held as a prisoner-of-war by Japan.
    - American radio report on the reestablishment of civilian Filipino government, 1945 February 26 (Record cabinet)
      Recording 262: Coverage of the handover of power from General MacArthur to the Commonwealth government. MacArthur and the Filipino president both speak.
      Sound quality is poor due to bad radio reception.
    - American radio reports from the Pacific around the time of the Battle of Okinawa, 1945 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Cut 383, CBS shot.
      Gene Ryder reports on the aircraft and fighting of the American forces against Japan.
      Part 2: Cut 384, Special Army shot for all nets
      Brigadier General Ernest Moore describes the accomplishment of his pilots in the war. The recording also features Major DeWitt Spain, one of the pilots.
    - American soldiers on Guam and radio personality sound recordings, 1945 December 18 (Record cabinet)
      A radio personality rehearses various advertisements and news stories.
      Four American soldiers recount what it is like to spend Christmas on Guam and send messages home to their families. The soldiers are Lieutenant George Hansen of Baltimore, Marines Private Yokem of Riverside (Conn.), radioman second class Alfred Gregory of Philadelphia (Penn.), and Ensign Richard Trull of Dunellen (N.J.).
    - Arthur Primm interviews Vice Admiral John H. Hoover, 1944 February 22 (Record cabinet)
      Vice Admiral Hoover talks about the importance for Iwo Jima. He also describes his experiences on D-Day.
    - Arthur Primm interviews crew members of the Bismarck Sea, 1945 March 30 (Record cabinet)
    - Arthur Primm interviews survivors of the Bismarck Sea, 1945 March 30 (Record cabinet)
    - Arthur Primm radio report, 1945 February 27 (Record cabinet)
      Recording 264: Primm reports about American air attacks on the Tokyo area.
    - Bob Brumby and Don Bell radio report, 1945 April 5 (Record cabinet)
      From Chungking, Brumby reports about Don Bell's return to journalism following time in a Japanese prison. Bell then speaks himself about his experiences, beginning with getting shot down by the Japanese.
    - Bob Brumby and Don Bell radio reports, 1945 June 24 (Record cabinet)
      Bob Brumby reports from Okinawa and Don Bell reports from Manila about the American advances in the Pacific.
    - Bob Brumby and Don Bell radio reports, number 594, 1945 July 1 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Bob Brumby reports on the Japanese being on the defensive against American and Australian forces.
      Part 2: Don Bell
    - Bob Brumby and Jack Mahon radio reports, 1945 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 743: Bob Brumby reports from Tokyo. He describes what it's like in the newly liberated Korea, from which he recently came.
      Jack Mahon reports from Tokyo on the recovery of Hideki Tōjō following his attempted suicide earlier that day.
    - Bob Brumby interviews three prominent journalism professionals, 1945 March 30 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 331: Bob Brumby interviews Wilbur S. Forest of the New York Herald-Tribune; Carl W. Ackerman, dean of the Columbia school of journalism; and Ralph E. McGill, editor of the Atlanta Constitution. They are touring world capitols to help ensure a free-flow of news across the world in the post-war era.
    - Bob Brumby radio report, 1945 April 11 (Record cabinet)
      Brumby reports on the relationship between the Chinese and communists, especially as it pertains to the Chinese delegation to the United Nations Conference on International Organization.
    - Bob Brumby radio report, 1945 April 13 (Record cabinet)
      Brumby reports on the reaction of the Chinese to the death of Franklin D. Roosevelt.
    - Bob Brumby radio report, 1945 March 16 (Record cabinet)
      Brumby reports on Japan's retreat from occupied areas.
    - Bob Brumby radio report, 1945 April 18 (Record cabinet)
      Brumby reports about the fighting Burma, saying one bout has finished and another has begun.
    - Bob Brumby radio report, 1945 July 20 (Record cabinet)
      Brumby describes the activities of Chinese resistance to Japan in Southern China near Canton and Hong Kong.
    - Bob Brumby radio report, 1945 April 4 (Record cabinet)
      Brumby reports from Chungking on the Chinese reaction to events at the United Nations Conference on International Organization in San Francisco. He concentrates on the importance of China's votes in the United Nations, how it relates to the Western powers, and the Soviet Union's role in all of the above.
    - Bob Brumby radio report from Okinawa, 1945 August 23 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 698: Brumby reports for the Mutual Broadcasting System. His focus is on what will become of Japanese soldiers as prisoners and what General MacArthur will do.
    - Bob Brumby radio report number 320, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Brumby reports from Chungking on the status of the war in the Burma area.
      The original disc carrier had two cuts of the same program, resulting in two digital files.
    - Bob Brumby radio report number 366A, 1945 April 4 (Record cabinet)
      Brumby reports about the Chinese reaction to preparations for the United Nations Conference of International Organization. He focuses on the one vote the United States will have as compared to the three votes the Soviet Union will have.
      There are two copies of this report on the original disc. The second is radially crossed out with wax, resulting in reduced sound quality and continual click/pop sounds throughout the recording.
    - Bob Brumby radio report number 379, 1945 April 6 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: False start
      Part 2: Brumby reports from Chungking about the Russian neutrality pact with Japan.
    - Bob Brumby radio report number 379A, 1945 April 6 (Record cabinet)
    - Bob Brumby radio report, 1945 July 14 (Record cabinet)
      Brumby reports for the Mutual Broadcasting System from Chungking on the resignation of General Chennault. He recalls the success of the Flying Tigers. He says the Chinese people will miss the general, saying they hold him to the same esteem as Patton, Eisenhower, and Wedemeyer.
    - Bob Brumby radio reports, 1945 July 12 (Record cabinet)
      Brumby reports from Chungking on the arrival of General Stratemeyer, the Chinese use of disappearing villages, and changing prices in China.
    - Bob Brumby radio reports, 1945 August 24 (Record cabinet)
      In the first two cuts, Brumby reports. The sound quality of these cuts is poor.
      In the third cut, Jack Mahon reports on the pending American landing in Tokyo Bay.
    - Bob Brumby radio reports, 1945 May 25-26 (Record cabinet)
      Brumby reports from Chungking on the Chinese armed forces. In the 25 May 1945 report, he compares them to boxers, fighting the Japanese with a new-found uppercut. The 26 May 1945 report is a longer, more general analysis of the Chinese soldier.
    - Bob Brumby radio report for the American Red Cross from Chungking, 1945 February 26 (Record cabinet)
      Recording 259. Please also see 58011_a_0010742; it is the same recording, though the dates on the disc are different.
      Brumby interviews two Red Cross employees that work in China.
      Poor sound quality due to radio interference during the cutting of the disc.
    - Bob Brumby radio report for the American Red Cross from Chungking, 1945 February 24 (Record cabinet)
      Recording 249. Please also see 58011_a_0010741; it is the same recording, though the dates on the disc are different.
    - Broadcast recordings, 1944 November 23-1945 (Record cabinet)
      Broadcasts concern the American forces in the Pacific Theater of World War II, behind-the-scenes look at radio production, and the success of the Soviet forces.
      CINCPAC POOL (PRIMM) Nov 23rd '44 (First B-29-Tokyo RAID)
      PRIMM FOR MBS CINPAC NOV 23 '44 #68
      "NPN8" points to the second most outer groove.
      Side B sounds like it was recorded sometime in 1945.
    - Broadcast recordings, 1946 March 19 (Record cabinet)
      In part 1, Jack McCoy reports about wives and children of soldiers arriving on Guam and reuniting with said soldiers.